<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Researches | Heterogeneity of Innovation</title>
    <link>https://roud.tech/research/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://roud.tech/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Researches</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://roud.tech/media/icon_hu9abfd8dca9502eafa578db8c63a4c8b0_7523_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Researches</title>
      <link>https://roud.tech/research/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://roud.tech/research/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://roud.tech/research/research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My research expertise builds around the following areas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Measurement of Science, Technology and Innovation&lt;/em&gt; How to measure innovation, dissemination of technologies or technological inequalities? My experience in innovation surveys, composite indexes, and scoreboards allows me to identify micro, macro, and meso-level indicators to capture firm strategies, development, change, technological upgrading, dissemination of advanced production technologies and organizational practices, impact of R&amp;amp;D, and research evaluation. I worked closely with OECD and been a national delegate to OECD TIP group, contributed to the revision of the international statistical standard for measuring innovation (OECD/Eurostat Oslo Manual) and numerous excercises of developing or interpreting STI-related indicators for applied or academic purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Business Innovation Studies:&lt;/em&gt; My expertise lies in understanding the diversity of innovation strategies, dimensionality of corporate innovation culture; openness (or closedness) of innovation, ecological innovation, and transformative innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Innovation, Technology and Society&lt;/em&gt;: I am experienced in studying user innovation and grassroots innovation, people&amp;rsquo;s attitudes towards new technologies and acceptance of new technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Governance of Innovation Systems&lt;/em&gt;: I specialize in technological upgrading and catch-up, transformative dynamics, path dependence and bounded change, efficiency of institutions and linkages, industry-science cooperation, patterns of innovation behavior, taxonomies of innovation, and evidence for systemic and diagnosis-based innovation policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Micro-)econometrics of Innovation and Technology and Causal Inference&lt;/em&gt; I have skills in machine learning-enabled studies of innovation and digital trace of innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am committed to exploring the complex context of STI and understanding the unique features that drive innovation. As such, I am excited to share my knowledge and collaborate with teams and organizations that seek to explore innovation capacities and develop evidence-based policies. Please feel free to write me  for further exploring our mutual interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;highlighted-contributions&#34;&gt;Highlighted contributions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roud, Vitaliy. &lt;em&gt;“Understanding the Heterogeneity of Innovation Modes: Performance Effects, Barriers, and Demand for State Support.”&lt;/em&gt; Technological Forecasting and Social Change 133 (2018): 238–53. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.techfore.2018.04.025&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.techfore.2018.04.025&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kratzer, Jan, Dirk Meissner, and Vitaliy Roud. &lt;em&gt;“Open Innovation and Company Culture: Internal Openness Makes the Difference.”&lt;/em&gt; Technological Forecasting and Social Change 119 (2017): 128–38. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.techfore.2017.03.022&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.techfore.2017.03.022&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roud, Vitaliy. &lt;em&gt;“Innovation Surveys as Evidence for Technological Upgrading and Catch-Up Studies.”&lt;/em&gt; In The Challenges of Technology and Economic Catch-up in Emerging Economies, 160–89. Oxford University Press, 2021. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1093/oso/9780192896049.003.0006&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1093/oso/9780192896049.003.0006&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roud, Vitaliy, and Valeriya Vlasova. &lt;em&gt;“Strategies of Industry-Science Cooperation in the Russian Manufacturing Sector.”&lt;/em&gt; The Journal of Technology Transfer, no. 45 (2020): 870–907. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10961-018-9703-3&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10961-018-9703-3&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thurner, Thomas Wolfgang, and Vitaliy Roud. &lt;em&gt;“Greening Strategies in Russia’s Manufacturing–from Compliance to Opportunity.”&lt;/em&gt; Journal of Cleaner Production 112 (2016): 2851–60. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2015.09.126&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2015.09.126&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;forthcomming&#34;&gt;Forthcomming:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gokhberg Leonid, Fursov Konstantin and Roud, Vitaliy. &lt;em&gt;“Technology measurement in statistics and beyond: reviving technological innovation concept.”&lt;/em&gt; In Handbook of Innovation Indicators and Measurement, 2nd edition, 240–259. Edward Elgar, 2023. ISBN: 978-1-80088-301-7&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find more here: 

&lt;a href=&#34;https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=jPGJPKoAAAAJ&amp;amp;hl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Google Scholar profile&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
