<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Researches | Heterogeneity of Innovation</title>
    <link>https://roud.tech/research/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://roud.tech/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Researches</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://roud.tech/media/icon_hu9abfd8dca9502eafa578db8c63a4c8b0_7523_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Researches</title>
      <link>https://roud.tech/research/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://roud.tech/research/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://roud.tech/research/research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My research expertise builds around the following areas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Measurement of Innovation: How to measure innovation, dissemination of technologies or technological inequalities? My experience in innovation surveys, composite indexes, and scoreboards allows me to identify micro, macro, and meso-level indicators to capture firm strategies, development, change, technological upgrading, dissemination of advanced production technologies and organizational practices, impact of R&amp;amp;D, and research evaluation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Business Innovation Studies: My expertise lies in innovation strategies, organizational culture for innovation, open innovation, ecological innovation, and transformative innovation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Innovation, Technology and Society: user innovation and grassroots innovation, people&amp;rsquo;s attitudes towards new technologies and acceptance of new technologies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Governance of Innovation Systems: I specialize in technological upgrading and catch-up, transformative dynamics, path dependence and bounded change, efficiency of institutions and linkages, industry-science cooperation, patterns of innovation behavior, taxonomies of innovation, and evidence for systemic and diagnosis-based innovation policy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Micro-)econometrics of Innovation and Technology and Causal Inference: I have skills in machine learning-enabled studies of innovation and digital trace of innovation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am committed to exploring the complex context of STI and understanding the unique features that drive innovation. As such, I am excited to share my knowledge and collaborate with teams and organizations that seek to explore innovation capacities and develop evidence-based policies. Please feel free to write me  for further exploring our mutual interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please, consider my academic contributions at the 

&lt;a href=&#34;https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=jPGJPKoAAAAJ&amp;amp;hl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Google Scholar profile&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
