<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Consultancies | Heterogeneity of Innovation</title>
    <link>https://roud.tech/consultancy/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://roud.tech/consultancy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Consultancies</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://roud.tech/media/icon_hu9abfd8dca9502eafa578db8c63a4c8b0_7523_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Consultancies</title>
      <link>https://roud.tech/consultancy/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consultancy/Policy Advice</title>
      <link>https://roud.tech/consultancy/consultancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://roud.tech/consultancy/consultancy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a seasoned consultant, I have had the opportunity to contribute to initiatives aiming to enhance policymaking, corporate strategies, drive organizational transformation. My contributions have often involved providing knowledge, organizing information, offering creative inputs,  performing comprehensive data processing and analysis and presenting
the work to the clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have data, I am good at extracting maximum meaning from it and turning it into a story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you need data, I can help with designing the tools to collect and analyze it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My skills cover all stages of data-driven decision making:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bluesky exploring and reviewing the research agenda and best practice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating guiding frameworks and concepts for indicator development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developing measurement strategies, designing and implementing surveys, complementing mixed methods processes that combine data and expert knowledge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analysis and modelling (from ETL to microeconometrics and machine learning)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visualise data and present findings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide interpretations and recommendations based on evidence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have experience with various tools such as R, Python, Quarto, advanced Excel/VBA and SQL (not to mention classic Stata, SPSS, etc.) and can use them to improve your data analysis workflows. I can work with a variety of data types, from survey microdata and aggregated international statistics to composite and aggregate indices, bibliometrics, and any other data we can collect using modern tools. I aim to bring the data findings in line with the current research agenda and practical discussions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am used to work in a timely and result-oriented manner. I look forward to potential collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;project-examples&#34;&gt;Project examples&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;measurement-of-sti&#34;&gt;Measurement of STI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Which internationally accepted methods can be used to measure business innovation through official statistics? Which widely applicable and informative metrics can capture the diverse contemporary models of innovation for decision-makers and researchers?&lt;/strong&gt; I took part in revising the international standard for statistical measurement of innovation, also known as the &lt;em&gt;OECD/Eurostat Guidelines for Collecting, Reporting and Using Data on Innovation (Oslo Manual 2018)&lt;/em&gt;, and contributed to the development of proposals for implementing the Manual into survey practice by Eurostat and OECD. I wrote two working papers that systematize the best practices of empirical studies of innovation strategies, such as open innovation and cooperation; and the sectoral diversity of innovation that goes beyond the manufacturing and service industries. These papers were intended to support the design of the final chapters of the Manual. I helped deliver survey guidelines and recommendations for the Eurostat Community Innovation Survey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How can the diffusion of advanced technologies and organisational concepts be tracked? What is the extent of technological inequality within and between industries? How well do innovation policies work? What are the opportunities and obstacles for collaboration between industry and academia?&lt;/strong&gt; I was the leader and principal researcher of the large-scale enterprise data collection project &lt;em&gt;Monitoring Survey of Innovation Behaviour of Enterprises&lt;/em&gt;, run by NRU HSE. The basis of the project was developed in collaboration with the European Manufacturing Survey (ISI Fraunhofer, Karlsruhe, Germany and research centres from 18 countries, 2009-2017).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can agriculture be described as an innovative industry? If so, how innovative is it compared to manufacturing?&lt;/strong&gt;. Innovation in agriculture is different from innovation in manufacturing. It is rarely developed in-house; production processes and the nature of innovation inputs and outputs have their own specificities. In addition, agriculture has its own language, which is very different from the innovation language of &amp;ldquo;locomotives&amp;rdquo; and high technology. I have addressed these challenges when contributing to the development of the &lt;em&gt;national innovation statistics for the agricultural sector&lt;/em&gt;. Based on global best practices and adopting the general recommendations of the Oslo Manual, I proposed methodologically consistent yet practically feasible ways to measure innovation in agriculture. These approaches have been implemented by the national statistical office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;performance-of-national-innovation-systems&#34;&gt;Performance of national innovation systems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is a country doing well in terms of innovation? How to get the most complete picture from dozens of indicators and how to identify the real bottlenecks and opportunities relevant for the foundations of evidence-based innovation policy?&lt;/strong&gt; I have contributed to &lt;em&gt;comprehensive overviews of the Russian national innovation system&lt;/em&gt;, provided chapters for the Global Innovation Index Analytical Report, 2012, 2016; Strategy 2020 for Socio-Economic Development of the Russian Federation; etc., provided statistical data for international statistical databases and outlooks (OECD, UNESCO), developed systems of indicators, KPIs and dashboards for monitoring long-term trends and policy evaluation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the framework conditions for research and development? What is the scope of business climate factors for doing scientific research and deriving applications for the economy?&lt;/strong&gt; I contributed to the qualitative-quantitative project &lt;em&gt;Doing Science&lt;/em&gt; to operationalise and measure the institutional factors that facilitate or hamper research and development. I developed the conceptual framework and the survey methodology to capture the attitudes and expectations of national R&amp;amp;D performers, the demand for policy support measures and the public perception of their effectiveness; led the analysis and presented the results to the Ministry of Science and Higher Education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;foresight&#34;&gt;Foresight&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can the state concentrate enough effort and resources to support the emergence and upscaling of a modern high-tech industry?&lt;/strong&gt; I was involved in the design and implementation of the &lt;em&gt;Technological Roadmap for the Light Emitting Diode Industry in the Russian Federation&lt;/em&gt;. My tasks included project coordination and team management, expert engagement and communication, framework development, expert input analysis and systematisation, and deliverables production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the consensus view of national experts on the technological future of the country and its positioning on the global technological frontier?&lt;/strong&gt; I participated in the first &lt;em&gt;National S&amp;amp;T Foresight&lt;/em&gt; in Russia, helping to conduct the large-scale Delphi survey. Focusing on the Information and Communication Technologies and Nanotechnologies sectors, I conducted desk research to structure the technology fields; interacted with experts; developed guidelines for focus groups and survey questionnaire design; processed data; communicated results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Further keywords:&lt;/em&gt; effects of innovation, evidence-based policymaking, policy evaluation, research performance evaluation, technology level, innovation climate, technology upgrading, intangible assets, whole-of-the-government approach, transformative policies, eco-innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
