<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Consultancies | Heterogeneity of Innovation</title>
    <link>https://roud.tech/consultancy/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://roud.tech/consultancy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Consultancies</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://roud.tech/media/icon_hu9abfd8dca9502eafa578db8c63a4c8b0_7523_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Consultancies</title>
      <link>https://roud.tech/consultancy/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consultancy/Policy Advice</title>
      <link>https://roud.tech/consultancy/consultancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://roud.tech/consultancy/consultancy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a seasoned team member in consultancy and policy advice projects, I have had the opportunity to contribute to initiatives aiming to enhance policymaking, corporate strategies, drive organizational transformation. My contributions have often involved providing knowledge, organizing information, offering creative inputs,  performing comprehensive data analysis and presenting the work to the clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My skills cover all stages of data-driven decision making, from initial bluesky explorations and creating guiding frameworks to setting up indicators and developing measurement strategies. This also includes analyzing and visualizing data, presenting findings, and offering interpretations and recommendations based on evidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am experienced with various tools like R, Python, Quarto, advanced Excel/VBA, and SQL (not to mention classical Stata, SPSS, etc.), and can use them to help improve your data analysis workflows. I can work with different types of data, from survey microdata and aggregate international statistics to composite and aggregate indexes, bibliometrics, and any other data we can gather using modern tools. I strive to align the data findings with the current research agenda and practical discussions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am used to work in a timely and result-oriented manner. I look forward to potential collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;project-examples&#34;&gt;Project examples&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;measurement-of-sti&#34;&gt;Measurement of STI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Revision of the international standard for statistical measurement of innovation — OECD/Eurostat Guidelines for Collecting, Reporting and Using Data on Innovation (Oslo Manual) and Proposals for putting Oslo Manual into Survey Practice (Eurostat, OECD, 2016–2018).&lt;/em&gt; Delivered two working papers that systematize best practices of the empirical studies of innovation strategies to support the design of final chapters of the Manual. Contributed to delivery of survey guidelines and recommendations for Eurostat Community Innovation Survey.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Monitoring Survey of Innovation Behavior of Enterprises (HSE, 2009–2022) in collaboration with the European Manufacturing Survey (ISI Fraunhofer, Karlsruhe, Germany and research centers from 18 countries, 2009–2017)&lt;/em&gt;. Head of project, organizer and analyst of large-scale enterprise survey on the innovation strategies, dissemination of technologies and organizational concepts, demand on policy support instruments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Developing innovation statistics for agriculture (Ministry of Agriculture of the Russian Federation, 2015–2016)&lt;/em&gt;.
Systematized international practice of innovation measurement in agriculture, adopted the general Oslo Manual recommendations for the specificity of the innovation in agricultural sector. Participated in introduction of the guidelines into the national innovation survey.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;performance-of-national-innovation-systems&#34;&gt;Performance of National innovation systems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Comprehensive overviews of the Russian National innovation system (chapters for Global Innovation Index Analytical Report, 2012, 2016; Strategy 2020 for Socio-Economic Development of the Russian Federation; etc., 2008–present).&lt;/em&gt;
Delivery of analytical reports, provision of statistical data for the international statistical databases and outlooks (OECD, UNESCO).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Doing Science: operationalizing and measuring climate for research and development (Ministry of Science and Education of the Russian Federation, 2017–2019).&lt;/em&gt; Developed the conceptual framework and the survey methodology to capture the attitudes and expectations of the national R&amp;amp;D performers the demand for policy support measures and public perception of their efficiency; lead the analysis and presented the results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;foresight&#34;&gt;Foresight&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Technological Roadmap for Light Emitting Diodes Industry in Russian Federation (Rusnano, 2008–2010)&lt;/em&gt;. Project coordination and team management, development of the framework, analysis and systematization of experts’ inputs, production of deliverables.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;National S&amp;amp;T Foresight (Ministry of Science and Education of the Russian Federation, 2006–2008)&lt;/em&gt;.
Developed the analytical architecture of the thematic areas of Information Technologies and Nanotechnologies; contributed to designing and running the Foresight procedurets for a national level Delphi survey, including desk-research; guidelines for focus groups; survey questionnaires and processing the data; communicating the results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
